

https://ethayer.design

ethayer.design@gmail.com

619-952-5081

Summary

My career started in San Diego as a post-production artist, but since moving to Denver in 2005, I have served in different design focused roles for video production, graphic design, and front-end development teams.

I want to be a key contributor to a product design or development team that cares deeply about accessibility, customer service, and UI/UX design systems.

Skills & Abilities

WEB DESIGN / FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

HTML • SCSS • JS • Vue.js • GraphQL • Hasura

I can develop responsive UI display patterns with a focus on performance and accessibility. I enjoy creating design systems, front-end architecture and inclusive UX. I am comfortable with modern front-end/backend frameworks or custom development.

TOOLS: VS Code, Git, CodePen, Pattern Lab, Storybook.js

VISUAL / USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN

Branding • User Discovery • UI • Prototypes • Styleguides

I have experience working in print, online and video design mediums. I believe that research and discovery produce the best outcome. Communication is vital to my process and I enjoy working closely with creative teams to craft the final result.

TOOLS: InVision, Sketch, Adobe CC (AE, AI, PS, XD)

CONTENT STRATEGY / ART DIRECTION

Design Sprints • Information Architecture • Wireframes

I find that concept creation and prototyping are the most exciting part in the design process. I can build interactive wireframes, code based mockups, and enjoy developing the creative direction behind the style and layout of page "content" or interactive elements.

TOOLS: InVision Whiteboard, Adobe XD, Sketch

linkedin.com/in/ethayerdesign

CODEPEN

codepen.io/ericthayer

Education

B.S. Media Arts - Platt College, San Diego, CAGraduated 2005 - focus: Video Production / Motion Graphics

A.A.S. Graphic Design - Platt College, San Diego, CA

Graduated 2003 - focus: Graphic / Web Design

Experience

12/2017 - current

Health Scholars - healthscholars.com

UI/UX Designer / Front-end Developer

- Work with teams to establish brand design systems and style guide
- Create and maintain web component system with Vue.js
- Establish VR UI design system with Unity UI Toolkit
- Build interactive prototypes, mockups, and wireframes
- Facilitate "Design Sprints" and VR interface design training

2015 - 2017

Freelance Designer - ethayer.design

UI/UX Designer / Front-end Developer

- Produced 2 front-end design systems for rapid Kentico development
- Established custom CSS framework for rapid prototyping
- Developed front-end architecture for 3 startups
- Created interactive wireframes and HTML based prototype templates
- Successfully revised 2 non-responsive code bases

2011 - 2015

The Navigators - navigators.org

Lead Designer / Front-end Developer - responsible for the design and development of organizational creative needs including: logo/branding creation, UI/UX design, customer support, client consultation and project management.

- Delivered 40+ responsive websites for internal departments and missions
- Optimized 20+ existing non-responsive websites for mobile use
- Created Bootstrap based framework for rapid Kentico CMS development
- Decreased development time by 40% with custom template system
- Eliminated the need for design and development outsourcing
- Established front-end documentation and guide lines for client discovery
- Served on IT department communications board

2010 - 2013

Defense Language Institute - dliflc.edu

Multimedia Specialist - responsible for the creation of training videos, motion/web graphics and iOS UI/content across multiple teams for the Department of the Army (Defense Foreign Language Center).

- Delivered 100+ training videos and graphic materials
- Contributed to the production of over 50+ iOS training applications
- Increased graphic optimization time by 35% with custom process
- Introduced very first responsive website template system
- Optimized 5+ existing non-responsive websites for mobile use
- Awarded commendation of service for "efficiency" 3 times

Training & Learning

2014 ArtifactConf + Atomic Design workshop, Platform14 • 2015 CSSDevConf, SassSummit
2016 RWD Summit, Front Utah, CSSDevConf • 2017 SVG Summit, Front Utah, CSSDevConf +
Design Systems workshop • 2018 UIE UX Immersion: Interactions
2019 SmashingConf • 2020 SmashingConf (online) • 2021 An Event Apart